<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Post-rsses on Shanaaz Trethewey </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://shanaaztrethewey.com/post/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 16:48:50 SAST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Likeability</title>
      <link>http://shanaaztrethewey.com/post/likeability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 16:48:50 SAST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shanaaztrethewey.com/post/likeability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes one person likeable and another not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do ask myself that question… and perhaps bordering on too many times.  When one sits on that boundary of asking the question, it may mean our own internal insecurities point at only ourselves.  We begin to second guess how, what and even why we said things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone once told me that everyone sub-consciously reacts to physical attributes.  So if you are the greatest guy out there but look like a nerd you may not always get the respect you deserve.  But it goes deeper than that – if you have a lumpy nose as oppose to a straight nose, you may be appear less approachable.  And if you have no jaw line as oppose to having a square jaw, people may not listen to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as I write this, I completely overtaken by the over-analysis, and complete judgement we all live with.  In a corporate world, people spend more time looking for reasons why they should be liked and also why they are blameless.  So if there are no other reasons as to why they should be scott-free on all accounts, why not just dislike someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I just want to do my job, and not feel like I have to be liked to just get my job done.  And people, just get over yourselves!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Introduction</title>
      <link>http://shanaaztrethewey.com/post/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 16:07:15 SAST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shanaaztrethewey.com/post/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess before one reads a blog of a stranger, you may want to know who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t, I’m happy for you skip this part&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a person just like you – doing my best to navigate what life has offered me, both in challenges and opportunities!  Of course, we are also different, I have things about my life that may not even come close to anything you may have experienced and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is who I am –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a woman, a wife and a mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a professional who is part of the workforce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a business owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a creative person that tries art projects, writing kids books, building things and am currently learning how to play the piano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked as an auditor, an investment banker, an operations and finance director, and a coach. And each of these experiences have shown me that there is commonality in the challenges we face – all leading to how we are seen, heard and how our needs are being met&amp;hellip;or more aptly – how our chosen actions to meet our needs are being interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this blog is all about this – just sharing, making observations and being human!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
